[Music]
Welcome to the Business Central launch
edition 2025 release wave 2. Now we will
show you new functionality in our
sustainability module about energy
tracking. My name is Alexander to
product manager and I have my colleague.
>> Hi, my name is Jacob Pang. I am also a
product manager working with Alexander.
>> Thank you. So before we go deep into new
functionality, I want to explain why we
did it. So with enabling energy
tracking, we enhanced our ESG
compliance. Why? Because of many of uh
regulations, for example, CSRD and other
require to report energy as well. So now
we will have full compliance with these
requirements. then it will definitely uh
help you to improve transparency about
energy sources. Uh even if this is
internally, it will improve your
operational efficiency especially to
track to show from where your energy is
coming. Uh it can uh help you for
tracking for reporting but not the least
company and brand reputation. So this is
important as well. So you can prove from
where your energy is coming and how much
emissions it makes. So
uh what processes are supported? You can
take track check your energy
consumptions in kilowatt hours from
sustainability journal or from purchase
documents. So you will have new fields.
You can enter information about uh your
energy consumption. Uh value will be
based on what you really uh consume. But
you can use some default values about
energy source. And if you want to use
default values about energy source,
actually you can do it manually. You can
choose manually on this uh uh journals
and the purchase documents. But you can
set up default values. Default values
will not be set up on account but the
sustainability account subcategory. So
what does it mean? You need to go for uh
sustainability account subcategory and
you need to choose energy source
information. Simple table where you will
have different uh source energy source
information. If this is nuclear, solar,
wind, power, coal, whatever you have as
a energy source information and then you
will have one additional field where you
will require entering energy in your
document or not. So you can if you you
can if you choose to enable energy value
required you cannot post document
without that. So this is important. Now
I will explain all situations how you
can post and when you are uh supposed to
enter manually. And one more information
you have energy on site to specify if
this energy source used to be generation
is on site or not. One additional field
is already in the system. So this is not
new. It can be used. This is a newable
energy field. You this is boolean field.
You can set to true or false. But this
is something what we had from early
beginning. So now let's look at the
rules. If you look into sustainability
account subcategory, we have these two
options to set up. If you said uh energy
value required is true. So if you mark
it and re renewable energy is false in
this case energy consumptions must have
value in sustainability journal
approaches documents. On the other side
if you have uh energy value required
true but renewable energy is true. So
this is complete renewable energy. This
is your choice. Maybe you have I don't
know 1% some small amount of energy uh
um uh consumed but this is on your
choice so you can choose what you can
enter there and energy value if required
is false this is your option so you can
choose to enter or this is your decision
if you want or not want other side you
can uh post energy consump consumption
even when emission do not have a value
in general without enabling uh energy
You cannot post sustainability u journal
without uh some of emissions uh to
related to this account. But if you have
value in energy, it allows you to post
uh only energy consumption later because
maybe in the moment when you posted
emissions, you forgot to post energy. So
in this case, you can post with the
empty uh field with the zero fields in
emissions but with a value in uh energy.
So now Deco will show you how it works
in the practice.
>> Yep. Thank you Alexander. Now we're
working in the sustainability hub. So
we'll go to the uh chart of
sustainability accounts and uh we'll
look at the boilers here. In the
subcategory
we'll show the details here. For boilers
we have already as Alexander mentioned
um chosen the um product here where we
have the gas. Of course we could have
chosen others but this in this category
it is gas. Now the next here is
important. This is what tovich mentioned
is this uh energy value required. You
have to click it or if you click it you
cannot post a sustainability journal
line without a value. Um in the case
that it is renewable energy as Alexander
mentioned then you can actually
overwrite that by clicking here. But in
this case we won't.
So we'll go back to start.
So now we'll look at sustainability and
sustainability journal.
So here we have the two line items, the
boiler and the heater.
We've already put in the manual entry
here. We've set in a unit of measure per
day and we've also put in an emission
CO2 equivalent of 100 for the boiler and
50 for the heater. In this case, um, we
cannot use the sustainability journal
line unless we have a power consumption
figure for the boiler. So, we're going
to put that in
here.
We'll go with 23 kW.
And now we're ready to post. So, once
we're posted, we can find u the entry
here in the sustainability ledger
entries. Back to you, Alexander.
>> Thank you, Jacob. And before we close
this session, uh I would like to remind
you we have this important general uh
busy central resources. So you can find
important information, you can learn
more about busy central. Further do not
forget to subscribe on LinkedIn uh
channel. So you can check weekly news uh
other announcements so on and also watch
more videos on YouTube akamsbc
YouTube. So you can find uh uh except
this video you can find uh many other
videos related to sustainability in this
edition other videos uh about other
functionalities in this edition previous
editions more than videos in YouTube.
So thank you for watching this session.